<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Images</title>
		<link>http://www.spacetelescope.org/</link>
		<description>Images Feed</description>
		<atom:link href="http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/feed/" rel="self"/>
		<language>en</language>
		<lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 13:45:48 +0100</lastBuildDate>
		<item>
			<title>Stretched out image of distant galaxy</title>
			<link>http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/opo1802a/</link>
			<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/news/opo1802a.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is an image from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.spacetelescope.org/&quot;&gt;NASA/ESA Hubble Space Telescope&lt;/a&gt; of the farthest galaxy yet seen in an image that has been stretched and amplified by a phenomenon called &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gravitational_lens&quot;&gt;gravitational lensing&lt;/a&gt;. The embryonic galaxy, named SPT0615-JD, existed when the Universe was just 500 million years old. Though a few other primitive galaxies have been seen at this early epoch, they have essentially all looked like red dots, given their small size and tremendous distances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, in this case, the gravitational field of a massive foreground &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Galaxy_cluster&quot;&gt;galaxy cluster&lt;/a&gt;, called SPT-CL J0615-5746, not only amplified the light from the background galaxy but also smeared the image of it into an arc (about 2 &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Minute_and_second_of_arc&quot;&gt;arcseconds&lt;/a&gt; long). Image analysis shows that the galaxy weighs in at no more than 3 billion solar masses (roughly 1/100th the mass of our Milky Way galaxy). It is less than 2500 light-years across, half the size of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Small_Magellanic_Cloud&quot;&gt;Small Magellanic Cloud&lt;/a&gt;, a satellite galaxy of the Milky Way. The object is considered prototypical of young galaxies that emerged during the epoch shortly after the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Big_Bang&quot;&gt;Big Bang&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Links:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://hubblesite.org/news_release/news/2018-02&quot;&gt;NASA Press Release&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 13:45:48 +0100</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/opo1802a/</guid>
			<enclosure length="263674" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/screen/opo1802a.jpg"/>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>View of the heart of our Milky Way from Earth</title>
			<link>http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/opo1801b/</link>
			<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/news/opo1801b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The vast edge-on stretch of our home galaxy, the Milky Way, is seen intersecting the night sky above the silhouetted Rocky Mountains in this photograph. The Milky Way noticeably widens at lower right. This wider area is the central hub, or bulge, of our galaxy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peering into a very narrow region of the core, astronomers used the NASA/ESA Hubble Space Telescope to study the compositions and motions of 10 000 Sun-like stars, as seen in the inset Hubble image. The analysis reveals that our galaxy's bulge is an unexpectedly dynamic environment of stars of various ages zipping around at different speeds, like travelers bustling about a busy airport. The study yields important new clues to the complexity of the central bulge and our Milky Way's evolution over billions of years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Hubble image is a composite of exposures taken in near-infrared and visible light with Hubble's Wide Field Camera 3. The observations are part of two Hubble surveys: the Galactic Bulge Treasury Program and the Sagittarius Window Eclipsing Extrasolar Planet Search.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The centre of our galaxy is about 26 000 light-years away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Links:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://hubblesite.org/news_release/news/2018-01&quot;&gt;NASA Press Release&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://spacetelescope.org/images/opo1801a/&quot;&gt;Hubble captures glittering crowded hub of our Milky Way&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 13:41:06 +0100</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/opo1801b/</guid>
			<enclosure length="694928" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/screen/opo1801b.jpg"/>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Hubble captures glittering crowded hub of our Milky Way</title>
			<link>http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/opo1801a/</link>
			<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/news/opo1801a.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This image from the NASA/ESA Hubble Space Telescope shows a sparkling jewel box full of stars captured the heart of our Milky Way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aging red giant stars coexist with their more plentiful younger cousins, the smaller, white, Sun-like stars, in this crowded region of our galaxy’s ancient central hub, or bulge. Most of the bright blue stars in the image are probably recently formed stars located in the foreground, in the galaxy's disc. Astronomers studied 10 000 of these Sun-like stars in archival Hubble images over a nine-year period to unearth clues to our galaxy’s evolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study reveals that the Milky Way’s bulge is a dynamic environment of variously aged stars zipping around at different speeds, like travelers bustling about a busy airport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers found that the motions of bulge stars are different, depending on a star’s chemical composition. Stars richer in elements heavier than hydrogen and helium have less disordered motions, but are orbiting around the galactic centre faster than older stars that are deficient in heavier elements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The image is a composite of exposures taken in near-infrared and visible light with Hubble’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://spacetelescope.org/about/general/instruments/wfc3/&quot;&gt;Wide Field Camera 3&lt;/a&gt;. The observations are part of two Hubble surveys: the Galactic Bulge Treasury Program and the Sagittarius Window Eclipsing Extrasolar Planet Search.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The centre of our galaxy is about 26 000 light-years away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Links:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://hubblesite.org/news_release/news/2018-01&quot;&gt;NASA Press Release&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://spacetelescope.org/images/opo1801b/&quot;&gt;View of the Heart of our Milky Way from Earth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 13:40:40 +0100</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/opo1801a/</guid>
			<enclosure length="618732" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/screen/opo1801a.jpg"/>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>A gargantuan collision</title>
			<link>http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/potw1802a/</link>
			<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/news/potw1802a.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2014, astronomers using the &lt;a href=&quot;http://spacetelescope.org&quot;&gt;NASA/ESA Hubble Space Telescope&lt;/a&gt; found that this enormous galaxy cluster contains the mass of a staggering three million billion Suns — so it’s little wonder that it has earned the nickname of “&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/El_Gordo_(galaxy_cluster)&quot;&gt;El Gordo&lt;/a&gt;” (“the Fat One” in Spanish)! Known officially as ACT-CLJ0102-4915, it is the largest, hottest, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://chandra.harvard.edu/photo/2014/elgordo/&quot;&gt;X-ray brightest&lt;/a&gt; galaxy cluster ever discovered in the distant Universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Galaxy_cluster&quot;&gt;Galaxy clusters&lt;/a&gt; are the largest objects in the Universe that are bound together by gravity. They form over billions of years as smaller groups of galaxies slowly come together. In 2012, observations from ESO’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eso.org/public/usa/teles-instr/paranal/&quot;&gt;Very Large Telescope&lt;/a&gt;, NASA’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://chandra.si.edu/&quot;&gt;Chandra X-ray Observatory&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://act.princeton.edu/&quot;&gt;Atacama Cosmology Telescope&lt;/a&gt; showed that El Gordo is actually composed of two galaxy clusters colliding at millions of kilometres per hour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The formation of galaxy clusters depends heavily on &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/dark_matter&quot;&gt;dark matter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dark_energy&quot;&gt;dark energy&lt;/a&gt;; studying such clusters can therefore help shed light on these elusive phenomena. In 2014, &lt;a href=&quot;http://spacetelescope.org&quot;&gt;Hubble&lt;/a&gt; found that most of El Gordo’s mass is concealed in the form of dark matter. Evidence suggests that El Gordo’s “normal” matter — largely composed of hot gas that is bright in the X-ray wavelength domain — is being torn from the dark matter in the collision. The hot gas is slowing down, while the dark matter is not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This image was taken by Hubble’s&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Advanced_Camera_for_Surveys&quot;&gt; Advanced Camera for Surveys&lt;/a&gt; and&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wide_Field_Camera_3&quot;&gt; Wide-Field Camera 3&lt;/a&gt; as part of an observing programme called&lt;a href=&quot;https://relics.stsci.edu/&quot;&gt; RELICS (Reionization Lensing Cluster Survey)&lt;/a&gt;. RELICS imaged 41 massive galaxy clusters with the aim of finding the brightest distant galaxies for the forthcoming&lt;a href=&quot;http://sci.esa.int/jwst/&quot;&gt; NASA/ESA/CSA James Webb Space Telescope&lt;/a&gt; (JWST) to study.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 06:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/potw1802a/</guid>
			<enclosure length="163091" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/screen/potw1802a.jpg"/>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Lasers and supermassive black holes</title>
			<link>http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/potw1801a/</link>
			<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/news/potw1801a.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This image, captured by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.spacetelescope.org/&quot;&gt;NASA/ESA Hubble Space Telescope&lt;/a&gt;’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.spacetelescope.org/about/general/instruments/wfc3/&quot;&gt;Wide Field Camera 3&lt;/a&gt; (WFC3), shows a galaxy named UGC 6093. As can be easily seen, UGC 6093 is something known as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Barred_spiral_galaxy&quot;&gt;barred spiral galaxy&lt;/a&gt; — it has beautiful arms that swirl outwards from a bar slicing through the galaxy’s centre. It is classified as an active galaxy, which means that it hosts an &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Active_galactic_nucleus&quot;&gt;active galactic nucleus&lt;/a&gt;, or AGN: a compact region at a galaxy’s centre within which material is dragged towards a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Supermassive_black_hole&quot;&gt;supermassive black hole&lt;/a&gt;. As this black hole devours the surrounding matter it emits intense radiation, causing it to shine brightly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But UGC 6093 is more exotic still. The galaxy essentially acts as a giant astronomical &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Laser&quot;&gt;laser&lt;/a&gt; that spews out light at microwave, not visible, wavelengths — this type of object is dubbed a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Megamaser&quot;&gt;megamaser&lt;/a&gt; (maser being the term for a microwave laser). Megamasers such as UGC 6093 can be some 100 million times brighter than &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Astrophysical_maser&quot;&gt;masers&lt;/a&gt; found in galaxies like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Milky_Way&quot;&gt;Milky Way&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hubble’s WFC3 observes light spanning a range wavelengths — from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Infrared&quot;&gt;near-infrared&lt;/a&gt;, through the visible range, to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ultraviolet&quot;&gt;near-ultraviolet&lt;/a&gt;. It has two channels that detect and process different light, allowing astronomers to study a remarkable range of astrophysical phenomena; for example, the UV-visible channel can study galaxies undergoing massive star formation, while the near-infrared channel can study &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Redshift&quot;&gt;redshifted light&lt;/a&gt; from galaxies in the distant Universe. Such multi-band imaging makes Hubble invaluable in studying megamaser galaxies, as it is able to untangle their intriguing complexity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 06:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/potw1801a/</guid>
			<enclosure length="113605" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/screen/potw1801a.jpg"/>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Hubble and HAWK-I explore a cluster with the mass of two quadrillion Suns</title>
			<link>http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/potw1752a/</link>
			<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/news/potw1752a.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This image shows something spectacular: a massive galaxy cluster that it is warping the space around it! The cluster, whose heart is at the centre of the frame, is named RCS2 J2327, and is one of the most massive clusters known at its distance or beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Massive objects such as RCS2 J2327 have such a strong influence on their surroundings that they visibly warp the space around them. This effect is known as &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gravitational_lens&quot;&gt;gravitational lensing&lt;/a&gt;. In this way, they cause the light from more distant objects to be bent, distorted, and magnified, allowing us to see galaxies that would otherwise be far too distant to detect. Gravitational lensing is one of the predictions of Einstein's &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/General_relativity&quot;&gt;theory of general relativity&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Strong_gravitational_lensing&quot;&gt;Strong lensing&lt;/a&gt; produces stunning images of distorted galaxies and sweeping arcs; both of which can be seen in this image. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Weak_gravitational_lensing&quot;&gt;Weak gravitational lensing&lt;/a&gt;, on the other hand, is more subtle, hardly seen directly in an image, and is mostly studied statistically — but it provides a way to measure the masses of cosmic objects, as in the case of this cluster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This image is a composite of observations from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eso.org/public/teles-instr/paranal-observatory/vlt/vlt-instr/hawk-i/&quot;&gt;HAWK-I&lt;/a&gt; instrument on ESO’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eso.org/public/teles-instr/paranal-observatory/vlt/&quot;&gt;Very Large Telescope&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.spacetelescope.org/&quot;&gt;NASA/ESA Hubble Space Telescope&lt;/a&gt;’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://spacetelescope.org/about/general/instruments/acs/&quot;&gt;Advanced Camera for Surveys&lt;/a&gt;. It demonstrates an impressively detailed collaborative approach to studying weak lensing in the cosmos. The study found RCS2 J2327 to contain the mass of two quadrillion Suns!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The diffuse blue and white image covering the picture shows a mass map. It is connected to the amount of mass thought to be contained within each region.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Links:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.spacetelescope.org/images/potw1752b/&quot;&gt;Galaxy Cluster RCS2 J2327&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.spacetelescope.org/images/comparisons/potw1752a/&quot;&gt;Comparison image: Hubble and HAWK-I explore a cluster with the mass of two quadrillion Suns&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2017 06:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/potw1752a/</guid>
			<enclosure length="134748" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/screen/potw1752a.jpg"/>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Galaxy cluster RCS2 J2327</title>
			<link>http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/potw1752b/</link>
			<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/news/potw1752b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This image shows the galaxy cluster RCS2 J2327. The mass of the cluster causes both s&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Strong_gravitational_lensing&quot;&gt;trong&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Weak_gravitational_lensing&quot;&gt;weak gravitational lensing&lt;/a&gt;, which can be used to calculate the mass of the cluster. This image is a composite of observations from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eso.org/public/teles-instr/paranal-observatory/vlt/vlt-instr/hawk-i/&quot;&gt;HAWK-I&lt;/a&gt; instrument on ESO’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eso.org/public/teles-instr/paranal-observatory/vlt/&quot;&gt;Very Large Telescope&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.spacetelescope.org/&quot;&gt;NASA/ESA Hubble Space Telescope&lt;/a&gt;’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://spacetelescope.org/about/general/instruments/acs/&quot;&gt;Advanced Camera for Surveys&lt;/a&gt;. It demonstrates an impressively detailed collaborative approach to studying weak lensing in the cosmos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Links:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.spacetelescope.org/images/potw1752a/&quot;&gt;Hubble and HAWK-I explore a cluster with the mass of two quadrillion Suns&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.spacetelescope.org/images/comparisons/potw1752a/&quot;&gt;Comparison image: Hubble and HAWK-I explore a cluster with the mass of two quadrillion Suns&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2017 06:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/potw1752b/</guid>
			<enclosure length="166230" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/screen/potw1752b.jpg"/>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Screenshot of the December 2017 issue of ESA/Hubble Science Newsletter</title>
			<link>http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/ann1715a/</link>
			<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/news/ann1715a.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;
</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/ann1715a/</guid>
			<enclosure length="905586" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/screen/ann1715a.jpg"/>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>ESA/Hubble publications in 2017</title>
			<link>http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/sci17008a/</link>
			<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/news/sci17008a.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hubble data was used in 743 peer reviewed papers published in 2017, as of 4 December. Out of these, 282 (38%) had an astronomer from an ESA Member State as the main author. This map shows the percentage distribution of published papers within the ESA Member States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ESA affiliation is based on the first author only. ESA affiliation is also only counted for the primary ESA country affiliated with the first author, i.e. if an author is affiliated with Italy and the United Kingdom, only Italy is attributed with the publication. Likewise, if an author is affiliated with China and France, France is attributed with the publication and counted in the ESA metrics.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 13:29:07 +0100</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/sci17008a/</guid>
			<enclosure length="132958" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/screen/sci17008a.jpg"/>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>JWST OTIS set for testing in space simulation chamber</title>
			<link>http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/sci17009a/</link>
			<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/news/sci17009a.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The combined Optical Telescope element / Integrated Science instrument module (OTIS) of the James Webb Space Telescope sits in front of the door to Chamber A, a giant thermal vacuum chamber located at NASA's Johnson Space Center.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 13:28:42 +0100</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/sci17009a/</guid>
			<enclosure length="227944" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/screen/sci17009a.jpg"/>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Still from Hubblecast 104: Illustrating Hubble’s discoveries</title>
			<link>http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/ann1714a/</link>
			<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/news/ann1714a.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a still from Hubblecast 104, talking about how the artist’s impressions for Hubble are created.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/ann1714a/</guid>
			<enclosure length="105088" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/screen/ann1714a.jpg"/>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>A snowstorm of stars</title>
			<link>http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/potw1751a/</link>
			<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/news/potw1751a.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s beginning to look a lot like Christmas in this NASA/ESA Hubble Space Telescope image of a blizzard of stars, which resembles a swirling storm in a snow globe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These stars make up the globular cluster Messier 79, located about 40 000 light-years from Earth in the constellation of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lepus_(constellation)&quot;&gt;Lepus (The Hare)&lt;/a&gt;. Globular clusters are gravitationally bound groupings of up to one million stars. These giant “star globes” contain some of the oldest stars in our galaxy. Messier 79 is no exception; it contains about 150 000 stars, packed into an area measuring just roughly 120 light-years across.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This 11.7-billion-year-old star cluster was first discovered by French astronomer &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pierre_M%C3%A9chain&quot;&gt;Pierre Méchain&lt;/a&gt; in 1780. Méchain reported the finding to his colleague &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charles_Messier&quot;&gt;Charles Messier&lt;/a&gt;, who included it in his catalogue of non-cometary objects: The &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Messier_object&quot;&gt;Messier catalogue&lt;/a&gt;. About four years later, using a larger telescope than Messier’s, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/William_Herschel&quot;&gt;William Herschel&lt;/a&gt; was able to resolve the stars in Messier 79 and described it as a “globular star cluster.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this sparkling Hubble image, Sun-like stars appear yellow-white and the reddish stars are bright giants that are in the final stages of their lives. Most of the blue stars sprinkled throughout the cluster are aging “helium-burning” stars, which have exhausted their hydrogen fuel and are now fusing helium in their cores.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 06:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/potw1751a/</guid>
			<enclosure length="423584" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/screen/potw1751a.jpg"/>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>NGC 5256 (ground-based view)</title>
			<link>http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/heic1720b/</link>
			<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/news/heic1720b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This wide-field image shows the pair of galaxies known as NGC 5256 and their surroundings as seen from the ground. In the upper left corner two planes crossed the image. Due to the long exposure their position lights cause long streaks in the final image.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/heic1720b/</guid>
			<enclosure length="209799" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/screen/heic1720b.jpg"/>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>An ongoing cosmic collision</title>
			<link>http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/heic1720a/</link>
			<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/news/heic1720a.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;NGC 5256 is a pair of galaxies in its final stage of merging. It was previously observed by Hubble as part of a collection of 59 images of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/archive/search/?category=560&amp;amp;adv=&amp;amp;facility=2&quot;&gt;merging galaxies&lt;/a&gt;, released on Hubble’s 18th anniversary on 24 April 2008. The new data make the gas and dust being whirled around inside and outside the galaxy more visible than ever before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This image is composed of data gathered with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.spacetelescope.org/about/general/instruments/acs/&quot;&gt;Advanced Camera for Surveys&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.spacetelescope.org/about/general/instruments/wfc3/&quot;&gt;Wide-Field Camera 3&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/heic1720a/</guid>
			<enclosure length="190460" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/screen/heic1720a.jpg"/>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Cosmic fireflies</title>
			<link>http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/potw1750a/</link>
			<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/news/potw1750a.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Galaxies glow like fireflies in this spectacular &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.spacetelescope.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;NASA/ESA Hubble Space Telescope&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt; image! This flickering swarm of cosmic fireflies is a rich cluster of galaxies called Abell 2163. Abell 2163 is a member of the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Abell_catalogue&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Abell catalogue&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, an all-sky catalogue of over 4000 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Galaxy_cluster&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;galaxy clusters&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. It is particularly well-studied because the material sitting at its core (its &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Intracluster_medium&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;intracluster medium&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;) exhibits exceptional properties, including a large and bright &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Radio_halo&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;radio halo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt; and extraordinarily high temperatures and X-ray &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Luminosity&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;luminosities&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. It is the hottest cluster in the catalogue! Observing massive clusters like Abell 2163 can contribute to the study of &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dark_matter&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;dark matter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, and provide a new perspective on the distant Universe via phenomena such as &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gravitational_lens&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;gravitational lensing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;This image was taken by Hubble’s &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://spacetelescope.org/about/general/instruments/acs/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Advanced Camera for Surveys&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt; and &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://spacetelescope.org/about/general/instruments/wfc3/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Wide-Field Camera 3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, partially for an extensive observing programme called &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://relics.stsci.edu/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;RELICS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. The programme is imaging 41 massive galaxy clusters to find the brightest distant galaxies, which will be studied in more detail using both current telescopes and the future NASA/ESA/CSA &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sci.esa.int/jwst/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;James Webb Space Telescope&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt; (JWST).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 06:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/potw1750a/</guid>
			<enclosure length="131609" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/screen/potw1750a.jpg"/>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Explosive tendencies</title>
			<link>http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/potw1749a/</link>
			<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/news/potw1749a.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Don’t be fooled! The subject of this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.spacetelescope.org/images/potw/&quot;&gt;Picture of the Week&lt;/a&gt;, ESO 580-49, may seem tranquil and unassuming, but this &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spiral_galaxy&quot;&gt;spiral galaxy&lt;/a&gt; actually displays some explosive tendencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In October of 2011, a cataclysmic burst of high-energy &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gamma_ray&quot;&gt;gamma-ray&lt;/a&gt; radiation — known as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gamma-ray_burst&quot;&gt;gamma-ray burst&lt;/a&gt;, or GRB — was detected coming from the region of sky containing ESO 580-49. Astronomers believe that the galaxy was the host of the GRB, given that the chance of a coincidental alignment between the two is roughly 1 in 10 million. At a distance of around 185 million light-years from Earth, it was the second-closest &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gamma-ray_burst&quot;&gt;gamma-ray burst&lt;/a&gt; (GRB) ever detected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gamma-ray bursts are among the brightest events in the cosmos, occasionally outshining the combined gamma-ray output of the entire &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Observable_universe&quot;&gt;observable Universe&lt;/a&gt; for a few seconds. The exact cause of the GRB that probably occurred within this galaxy, catalogued as GRB 111005A, remains a mystery. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gamma-ray_burst_progenitors#Collapsar_model&quot;&gt;Several&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tidal_disruption_event&quot;&gt;events&lt;/a&gt; are known to lead to GRBs, but none of these explanations appear to fit the bill in this case. Astronomers have therefore suggested that ESO 580-49 hosted a new type of GRB explosion — one that has not yet been characterised.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 06:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/potw1749a/</guid>
			<enclosure length="200371" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/screen/potw1749a.jpg"/>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>ESA’s Gaia satellite</title>
			<link>http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/heic1719f/</link>
			<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/news/heic1719f.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;ESA’s Gaia satellite is a space telescope designed to measure the positions of billions of stars with unprecedented precision. Gaia was launched on 19 December 2013 and is located at the L2 Lagrange point — the same location that the upcoming NASA/ESA/CSA James Webb Space Telescope will have.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 17:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/heic1719f/</guid>
			<enclosure length="189133" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/screen/heic1719f.jpg"/>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Wide-field image of the sky around the Sculptor Dwarf Galaxy</title>
			<link>http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/heic1719d/</link>
			<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/news/heic1719d.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This image of the sky around the Sculptor Dwarf Galaxy was created from images from the Digitized Sky Survey 2. The galaxy appears as a small faint cloud, close to the centre of the image.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 17:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/heic1719d/</guid>
			<enclosure length="252781" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/screen/heic1719d.jpg"/>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Sculptor Dwarf Galaxy (ground-based view)</title>
			<link>http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/heic1719c/</link>
			<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/news/heic1719c.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Sculptor Dwarf Galaxy is one of the Milky Way’s neighbouring dwarf galaxies. Like all large galaxies, the Milky Way is thought to have formed from smaller galaxies in the early Universe. This image is composed from data from the Digitized Sky Survey 2.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 17:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/heic1719c/</guid>
			<enclosure length="424103" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/screen/heic1719c.jpg"/>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Hubble observing the Sculptor Dwarf Galaxy</title>
			<link>http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/heic1719e/</link>
			<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/news/heic1719e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This image shows the Sculptor Dwarf Galaxy as it is seen from the ground with the Digitized Sky Survey 2. The two insets show the two pointings of Hubble that were used in the latest discovery, using data from both the NASA/ESA Hubble Space Telescope and ESA’s Gaia satellite.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 17:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/heic1719e/</guid>
			<enclosure length="355834" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/screen/heic1719e.jpg"/>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Hubble’s view of the Sculptor Dwarf Galaxy (pointing 1)</title>
			<link>http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/heic1719a/</link>
			<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/news/heic1719a.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This image shows a small part of the Sculptor Dwarf Galaxy, a satellite galaxy of the Milky Way, situated only about 300 000 light-years away from Earth. This is one of two different pointings of the telescope that were used in a study combining data from the NASA/ESA Hubble Space Telescope and ESA’s Gaia satellite to measure the 3D motion of stars in this galaxy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 17:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/heic1719a/</guid>
			<enclosure length="362045" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/screen/heic1719a.jpg"/>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Hubble’s view of the Sculptor Dwarf Galaxy (pointing 2)</title>
			<link>http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/heic1719b/</link>
			<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/news/heic1719b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This image shows a small part of the Sculptor Dwarf Galaxy, a satellite galaxy of the Milky Way, situated only about 300 000 light-years away from Earth. This is one of two different pointings of the telescope that were used in a study combining data from the NASA/ESA Hubble Space Telescope and ESA’s Gaia satellite to measure the 3D motion of stars in this galaxy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 17:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/heic1719b/</guid>
			<enclosure length="341308" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/screen/heic1719b.jpg"/>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Streaks and stripes</title>
			<link>http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/potw1748a/</link>
			<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/news/potw1748a.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;This picturesque view from the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://spacetelescope.org&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;NASA/ESA Hubble Space Telescope&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt; peers into the distant Universe to reveal a &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Galaxy_cluster&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;galaxy cluster&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt; called Abell 2537. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Galaxy clusters such as this one contain thousands of galaxies of all ages, shapes and sizes, together totalling a mass thousands of times greater than that of the Milky Way. These groupings of galaxies are colossal — they are the largest structures in the Universe to be held together by their own &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gravity&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;gravity&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Clusters are useful in probing mysterious cosmic phenomena like &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dark_matter&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;dark matter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;and &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dark_energy&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;dark energy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, the latter of which is thought to define the geometry of the entire Universe.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; There is so much matter stuffed into a cluster like Abell 2537 that its gravity has visible effects on its surroundings. Abell 2537’s gravity warps the very structure of its environment (&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spacetime&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;spacetime&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;), causing light to travel along distorted paths through space. T&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;his phenomenon can produce a &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gravitational_lens&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;magnifying effect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, allowing us to see objects that lie behind the cluster and are thus otherwise unobservable from Earth. Abell 2537 is a particularly efficient &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gravitational_lens&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;lens&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, as &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;demonstrated by the stretched stripes and streaking arcs visible in the frame. These smeared shapes are in fact galaxies, their light heavily distorted by the gravitational field of Abell 2537.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;This spectacular scene was captured &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;by Hubble’s &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.spacetelescope.org/about/general/instruments/acs/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Advanced Camera for Surveys&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt; and &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.spacetelescope.org/about/general/instruments/wfc3/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Wide-Field Camera 3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt; as part of an observing programme called &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://relics.stsci.edu/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;RELICS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 06:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/potw1748a/</guid>
			<enclosure length="256041" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/screen/potw1748a.jpg"/>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Cosmic snake pregnant with stars</title>
			<link>http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/potw1747a/</link>
			<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/news/potw1747a.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This NASA/ESA Hubble Space Telescope image reveals the Cosmic Snake, a distant galaxy peppered with clumpy regions of intense star formation that appear warped by the effect of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gravitational_lens&quot;&gt;gravitational lensing&lt;/a&gt;. This giant arc-like galaxy is actually behind the huge &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Galaxy_cluster&quot;&gt;galaxy cluster&lt;/a&gt; MACSJ1206.2-0847, but thanks to the cluster’s gravity, we can see it from Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Light from the distant, high-&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Redshift&quot;&gt;redshift&lt;/a&gt; galaxy arrives at Earth, having been distorted by the gigantic gravitational influence of the intervening cluster. Fascinatingly, instead of making it more difficult to perceive cosmological objects, such strong lensing effects improve the resolution and depth of an image by magnifying the background object. Sometimes gravitational lensing can even produce multiple images of the object as light is bent in different directions around the foreground cluster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using Hubble, astronomers recently looked at several such images of the Cosmic Snake, each with a different level of magnification. Using this technique, the galaxy and its features could be studied on different scales. The highest-resolution images revealed that giant clumps in high-redshift galaxies are made up of a complex substructure of smaller clumps, which contributes to our understanding of star formation in distant galaxies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Link:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.spacetelescope.org/images/potw1747b/&quot;&gt;Galaxy cluster MACSJ1206&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41550-017-0295-x&quot;&gt;Science paper by Cava et al.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 06:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/potw1747a/</guid>
			<enclosure length="236217" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/screen/potw1747a.jpg"/>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Galaxy cluster MACSJ1206</title>
			<link>http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/potw1747b/</link>
			<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/news/potw1747b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This image shows the galaxy cluster MACSJ1206.2-0847. The cluster is so far away, it took the light from the cluster more than 4.5 billion years to reach Earth. But the cluster itself is not even the most distant object in this image. Light from even more distant, high-&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Redshift&quot;&gt;redshift&lt;/a&gt; galaxies arrives at Earth, having been distorted by the gigantic gravitational influence of the intervening cluster. Objects, otherwise faint and tiny, get brighter and are magnified. Sometimes gravitational lensing can even produce multiple images of the object as light is bent in different directions around the foreground cluster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of these galaxies is the Cosmic Snake — clearly visible as a stretched object to the right of the central galaxy. This image of the Cosmic Snake is actually composed by four elongated and stretched images of the southern half of the source galaxy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Link:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.spacetelescope.org/images/potw1747a/&quot;&gt;Cosmic snake pregnant with stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 06:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/potw1747b/</guid>
			<enclosure length="168067" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/screen/potw1747b.jpg"/>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>